# **GESER DUGAROV, Ph.D.**

email: geserdugarov@gmail.com

**mobile**: +7-913-703-1014

languages: English (advanced), Russian (native)

**location**: Novosibirsk, Russia

### **SUMMARY**

Made transition to data-driven R&D in the IT industry after 12 yrs in fundamental research. Holds a degree of a Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Geophysics. Author and coauthor of more than 50 publications. Experienced in project management.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python, Docker, Git, Linux, Matlab

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

ML Research Engineer, Digital Research (spinoff of Digital Clouds)

II/2022 - current

• Vehicles monitoring (CV) in the construction industry. Project manager role.

# Senior Researcher,

<u>Trofimuk Institute of Petroleum Geology and Geophysics</u>

X/2009 – current

- Experience of technology transfer from fundamental research to business. Team leader role.
- 5 years in a row of personal projects supporting by main foundations (2017-2021).
- 4 graduate students: 3 MSc (2022\*2, 2020), 1 BSc (2020).
- "The best young researcher in Earth science organizations" award (2019).

Research Associate (II/2014 – IV/2019), Research Assistant (X/2009 – II/2014)

## **EDUCATION**

PhD, Geophysics, X/2009 – XII/2013

Trofimuk Institute of Petroleum Geology and Geophysics SB RAS

10001 1111000

(4 years)

MSc, Computational and Applied Mathematics, IX/2004 – VI/2009

Novosibirsk State University (5 years)

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- Deep Learning Specialization, Coursera (2021).
- Machine Learning, Coursera (2021).

### **PROJECTS**

- XII/2019 VIII/2021 AVAZ inversion of local object anisotropy parameters from 3D seismic data *Role*: **project manager**. *Team size*: 7. Customer: NTC NIS-Naftagas, Serbia.
- VII/2019 VI/2021 Acoustic properties and internal structure of hydrate-bearing coal samples *Role*: **head of the project**. *Team size*: 5. Supported by RSF, grant No. <u>19-77-00068</u>.

## **HONORS AND AWARDS**

- Trofimuk Memorial Medal Award (2021).
- "The best young researcher in Earth science organizations" (2019).

#### **HOBBIES**

- Going to the gym on a regular basis (since 2019).
- Reading developmental psychology and business management books.

Updated: 28.07.2022, the last version

